本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  板栗桑
・ 翻译  卫老哥
■
・ 翻译  紫玉
・ 翻译  Freeyeung
■
・ 翻译  天朝直属
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  宅女之后
・ 翻译  艾瑞卡
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  灰灰是菇凉
译  面条打包子
somehacker
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
■
・ 翻&校  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  凭陵新月  Kallen  Sagelibra  sweet宝宝  阿包  凭陵新月  Kallen  Sagelibra  sweet宝宝  阿包  凭陵新月  Kallen  Sagelibra  sweet宝宝  阿包  凭陵新月  Kallen  Sagelibra  sweet宝宝
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第十四集
■
获取额外信号
发现财物  [沙特前国王]伊本沙特匕首
估算价值  260万美元
音频拦截
主体  布沙尔  阿兰
我是布沙尔特工
This is Agent Bouchard.
布沙尔 阿兰
单位 国际刑警
职位                   特别罪案科主管
艺术品盗窃及贩运
音频拦截
主体  布沙尔  阿兰
我们已经羁押了一名嫌犯
We have a suspect in custody
但失物并没有找到
but have not recovered the artifact.
我相信窃贼仍然在逃
I believe our thief is still at large.
欢迎回来  里瑟先生
Welcome back, Mr. Reese.
看得出你的意大利之行在着装方面收获颇丰
I see your time in Italy was a sartorial success.
怎么说呢
What can I say?
新装  新人
New suit, new man.
新号码
New number.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我很希望有时间办个欢迎会
I do wish we had time for a homecoming,
但我们一小时前刚收到个号码
but we just received one about an hour ago.
凯莉・林
Meet Kelly Lin.
出生于上海  基本上在海外长大
Born in Shanghai, raised mostly abroad,
最近刚移民到美国
and recently immigrated to the U.S.,
反正她签证文件上是这么说的
or so says her visa paperwork.
她六个月前加入美国国籍
She naturalized as a citizen six months ago.
-她是间谍吗  -有可能
- Is she a spy? - Certainly possible.
现在  她在城里当宴会策划人
Right now, she's working as a professional event planner in the city.
她声誉很好  相当出色
Based on her international reputation, she's quite good.
我在网上找到了她的简历
I found her resume online.
推荐信无可挑剔
Impeccable references.
最容易接近宴会策划人的方法
Easiest way to get close to an event planner
莫过于出席宴会了
is to attend an event.
擅离职守  搭机旅行  脸不红气不喘啊
AWOL and air travel, and he hasn't missed a beat.
林女士受雇负责一场展览开幕
Ms. Lin has been hired to run the new exhibit opening
在大都会历史博物馆
at the Metropolitan Museum of History.
用电脑上略动手脚
A bit of clever computer work
把肖女士加到白金贵宾名单
put Ms. Shaw on the platinum guest list.
我就喜欢喝小酒吃小点
I'm a sucker for watered-down booze and a mini-quiche.
我是捐赠人
As a donor who rsvp'd,
你做我的携伴  里瑟先生
you'll be my plus-one, Mr. Reese.
随意正式礼服
Black tie optional.
我会熨一下我的礼服
I'll steam my tux.
擦一下我的
And oil my--
芬奇  我的武器呢
Finch, where's my spare weapon?
一星期前被我转到历史区了
I moved it to the history section a week ago.
更新下你的军械库吧  约翰
Update your arsenal, John.
看来暴风雨还没过去  里瑟先生
It appears that the storm has yet to pass, Mr. Reese.
你需要雨伞吗
Will you be needing an umbrella?
收起来能当战术武器用就行  芬奇
Only if it doubles as a tactical weapon, Finch.
这个给肖女士
I'll give this one to Ms. Shaw.
我一路冲过去得了
I'll just make a dash for it.
手工缝制扣眼
Hand-sewn button holes,
包括衣领上的那个
including one on the lapel.
无可挑剔的完美工艺
impeccable craftsmanship.
詹尼向来精致入微
I see that Gianni has spared no detail.
我得提升下档次
I gotta raise my game up
跟你一起看着才配啊  芬奇
if I gotta be seen with you, Finch.
这个就像系鞋带  里瑟先生
It's just like a shoelace, Mr. Reese.
如果有点荒疏的话  可以在腿上
I find that it helps if you practice on a leg
或者裸颈上练习一下
or a collarless neck if you're out of practice.
我闭着眼睛能倒拆点45  芬奇
I can field strip a .45 upside down in the dark, Finch.
我肯定能搞定个领结
I think I can handle a bow tie.
当然
Of course.
这是蝴蝶结还是蝙蝠结
Is it butterfly or batwing?
当我没说  你慢慢来
Never mind, take your time.
真不想打扰你们的春宵缠绵  先生们
Hate to interrupt this mildly erotic moment, gents,
不过请柬上要我们别迟到
But the invitation advises us not to be late.
怎么了
What?
看来你更新了你的军械库嘛  肖
I see you've updated your arsenal, Shaw.
姐镇得住
I can work it,
包里还有把点38呢
along with the .38 I've got in my handbag.
瞧好儿吧
So watch it.
能走了吗
Can we go now?
特别展览吗  芬奇
Special exhibit, Finch?
世界各地的博物馆合作
A partnership of museums around the world
把馆藏的珍品文物
loaned some of their most significant cultural artifacts
汇聚到这一个展览
to use in this one single exhibit.
这可不常有
Something like that doesn't happen often.
罪孽深重
Abomination.
侵吞文物
Misappropriation.
外面火药味有点浓
Sounds pretty aggressive out there.
他们认为文物
They believe that cultural artifacts
应该属于孕育它的文明
belong to the cultures they came from.
听着就一群嬉皮士加艺术呆子
Sounds like a bunch of hippies and art nerds to me.
大都会历史博物馆
世界舞台
人类文明庆典
还是可能威胁到凯莉
Still, they could be a threat to Kelly.
她负责本场宴会
She is running the event.
说曹操
Speak of the devil.
凯莉  怎么回事
Kelly, what am I hearing?
安全部追我屁股后边问
I've got head of security on my ass
宴会场地干冰冷却器的事
about coolers of dry ice in the event space.
是的  先生  我知道
Yes, sir, I've heard that too.
我没有订购
I don't have a P.O. for those.
应该是送错货了
I think it was a shipping mistake.
我可不付钱给送错的货
I won't pay for the mistake.
我和供货商谈过了
I spoke to my suppliers,
不会收博物馆一分钱
the museum won't be charged a dime.
而且  他们还答应
Plus, they've offered to upgrade
把今晚的香槟
tonight's champagne selection
从皇牌升级成桃红
from yellow label to rose.
桃红香槟确实不错
I do enjoy a nice rose.
天啊  亲爱的
Oh, my. Dear?
芬奇  这儿看不出一点危险
Finch, there's no sign of danger in here,
除了鲜虾泡芙
not counting the shrimp puffs.
你刚才的举动真棒
That was an impressive move.
免了我叫急救人员的麻烦了
Saved me having to get paramedics in here.
正确的地点  正确的时间
Right place, right time.
你知道他是谁吗
Do you know who he was?
沃伦・齐姆  投行大老板
Warren Zimm, big-time investment banker.
S01E16贝乐&齐姆投资银行
想想吧  整个商业帝国差点毁于一旦
Think, that whole empire down the drain.
就因为一只小虾米
From one cunning shellfish.
你的口音很优美
You know, you have a beautiful accent,
我好像听过  但想不起来
and I have an ear for it, but I can't place it.
你是哪里人
Where are you from originally?
我在香港待过几年
I spent a few years in a Hong Kong,
国际学校
some international schooling.
之后  就一直东走走  西晃晃
Since then, I've picked up traces from a little bit of everywhere.
祝你今晚愉快
Enjoy the rest of your evening.
好的  谢谢
Oh, yes, thank you.
凯莉如鹤立鸡群
Kelly's good in this crowd.
妩媚动人  进退得体
Charming, casually evasive.
什么人会想要害她呢
Who would want to put a bull's-eye on her?
我们并不确定是有人要害她
We don't know that anyone did, yet.
冉  哈罗德
Wren, Harold.
没问题  哈罗德・冉  及其携伴
Of course, Harold Wren and guest.
今晚请带好这个
Please keep these on tonight,
证明您已经签到
to show you're all checked in.
天啊  他帅得销魂荡魄
Oh, my, he's gorgeous.
讲究的场面  讲究的宾客
Fancy stuff, fancy guests.
这工作可以让凯莉接触到这一切
A job like this could give Kelly access to all of them,
甚至包括他们阴暗的小秘密
and maybe all of their dirty little secrets.
里瑟先生  你知道这是什么吗
Mr. Reese, do you know what this is?
这是诺埃尔古抄本
It's the Nowell Codex.
欧洲文学三大英雄史诗之一《贝奥武夫》  该抄本现存大英博物馆中
有上千年历史了
It's over 1,000 years old.
真漂亮  不过我觉得
Yeah, it's beautiful, but I think
我们还是重点关注大奖吧
we should keep our eyes on the prize in here,
你说呢
don't you think?
各位  各位
Everyone, everyone,
看来出了点问题
there seems to be a problem.
请待在原地等
Please stay where you are until--
-里瑟先生  -我去看看
- Mr. Reese? - I’m on it.
不好意思  借过
Excuse me. Pardon me.
不好意思
Excuse me.
芬奇  是干冰炸弹
Finch, they're dry ice bombs,
和水一起放在了密封的冷却器里
packed in airtight coolers with water.
正好能制造出烟雾
And the perfect smoke screen.
但谁送进博物馆的呢
But who delivered them to the museum?
可能是那些抗议者
It could be the protestors.
我不觉得  肖女士
I don't think so, Ms. Shaw.
我觉得有人要带着[现代绘画之父]塞尚真迹跑了
I think someone's trying to make off with the Cezanne.
站住
Stop!
看到了  芬奇
Got it, Finch.
正确的地点  正确的时间
Right place, right time?
看来我们都说谎了
I guess we're both liars, huh?
小子们
Boys,
说出来你们都不能信  我知道窃贼是谁了
you're not gonna believe this, but I know who the thief is.
抱歉  小姐  犯罪现场
I'm sorry, miss, crime scene.
警官  我正在宴会中工作
Officer, I was just working this event
忽然就爆炸冒烟一团乱
when boom, smoke, chaos.
人们又跑又叫的
People were running, screaming.
我包都没拿就被挤出去了
I got swept out the door without my bag.
先生  拜托
Sir, please--
小姐  都凌晨一点了
Miss, it's 1:00 a.m.,
你要怎么才肯住嘴啊
what can I do to make you stop talking?
让我去拿包
Let me get my bag.
我保证  我什么都不碰
I promise, I won't touch anything
不会打扰你们那些什么现场调查员  我发誓
or bump into any of your C.S.I. guys, I swear.
我记得工作人员放包的桌子
I remember what table the staff put their bags under.
找到了凯莉的告诉我
Let me know if you find Kelly's.
但愿她忙中出错
I hope in the rush she forgot it,
偷完画后落下了
after she grabbed that painting.
还有更好的  芬奇
I'll do you one better, Finch.
我拿到了她的包和她的电脑
I got her bag and her computer.
她当然是来偷塞尚的
Of course, she went for the Cezanne.
她很有品味
She has good taste.
我们国际刑警追查她一年多了
I've been hunting her for Interpol for over a year.
女性  25到35岁  亚裔
Female, 25 to 35 of Asian ethnicity,
我认为是华人
I believe Chinese.
就这点线索了
That's all anyone can say, really.
从没人见过她的脸
No one's ever gotten a good look at her face.
六个月前我差点在迪拜抓到她
I almost had her in Dubai six months ago.
我顺着她的一本护照追查到了纽约
I came to New York following a passport of hers,
查不下去时
dead end,
接到了你们的电话
when I got this call.
她很难追踪
She's hard to track.
她会用到帮手
She uses accomplices,
付钱让流浪汉去坐一小会儿牢
vagrants that she pays off if they'll do a little jail time.
她随后就会杀了他们  明白吗
She kills them after, you see?
让你的警探们准备好
Tell your detectives to be ready.
这女人所到之处  必有尸体
Anywhere this woman goes, bodies follow.
你听到那些诱饵和死去的帮手了吗
You hear that about decoys and dead accomplices?
凯莉很危险
Kelly's dangerous.
警卫还活着
The guard is still alive.
我们目前也没见她下重手伤人
And we haven't seen her hurt anyone seriously yet.
但既然我们收到了她的号码
But if we received her number,
恐怕也只是时间问题了
it could just be a matter of time.
我已经看过了  纯属浪费时间
I already looked, waste of time.
里面的一切都只能证明她的宴会策划人身份
Everything on there supports her cover as an event planner:
送货订单啊  收据啊  如此之类
Shipping orders, receipts, that kind of thing.
她弃之不顾  肯定是毫无价值
If she ditched it, it's worthless.
也许关键不在于电脑里边的内容
Maybe it's not about what's on the device,
而在于它去过哪里
but rather where it's been.
现在所有的便携电脑都装有GPS芯片
All portable devices have GPS chips these days.
我们要追踪她
If we're trying to track her down,
可以从她常去的地方入手
it will likely be some place she frequents.
这里  珍珠街
There, down on Pearl Street.
侦探小说之父埃德加・爱伦・坡的短篇侦探小说
一间酒吧  叫"失窃的信"  真应景
A bar called, "The Purloined Letter." That's appropriate.
去看看凯莉跟谁喝酒
Let's go see who Kelly meets for drinks.
鉴于我们的距离  既然凯莉有可能在酒吧里
Given our proximity and the likelihood that Kelly is in that bar,
我可以用软件黑进
I can use software to bluejack
里面所有人的手机
every phone line in the place.
-哥们  我告诉你  -不是
- Dude, I'm telling you-- - No.
-打扰下  打扰下  给我来杯啤酒好吗  -不是
- Excuse me, excuse me, can I get a beer, please? - No.
-但我就是忘不了她  -不是
- But I just can't get her out of my-- - No.
我拿到画了
I got the painting.
慢着  找到了
Wait, I found her.
这个绝对是凯莉
It's definitely Kelly.
我让你联系的人
The guys I put you in touch with,
拿到你要的东西了吗  干冰
you get what you wanted, the ice?
正好在需要的位置上
It was where it needed to be.
我不得不打伤了一名警卫  西里尔
I had to hurt a guard, Cyril.
他应该让开路的
He should've stayed out of the way.
你的塞尚
Your Cezanne.
满意了吗
Satisfied?
你满意就好  [捷克语]甜心
Only if you are, milacku.
结束
We're done here.
我游历过全世界  你也是
I've been all around the world. So have you.
但你离结束还早着呢
But you're far from done.
我在布拉格的伙伴们很欣赏你的工作
My associates in Prague are appreciative of all your work.
但下一票
But this next job--
下一票可是杰作  娇
this next job is a masterpiece, Jiao.
做成了  你要什么都行
You have everything to gain from it
反之  你什么都会失去
and just as much to lose.
那我就不浪费时间跟你聊天了
Then I shouldn't waste any more time talking to you.
她用的钥匙  芬奇
She used a key, Finch.
那至少她不是进去抢劫
At least we know she isn't robbing the place.
我似乎找到了凯莉的公寓
I think I found Kelly's apartment--
只有一个住户没有铭牌
only one without a name.
在酒吧里  那个跟凯莉面谈的人
In the bar, the man Kelly was meeting
称呼她"娇"
called her "Jiao."
"凯莉・林  宴会策划人"反正查不下去了
We know that "Kelly Lin, event planner" is a dead end.
试试查下"林娇"
Let's take a look into Jiao Lin.
有许多网站的数据显示
It seems there are a number of sites with data
有一名前奥运会体操运动员
relating to a former Olympic gymnast
林娇  曾经代表中国国家队出赛
Jiao Lin, who competed for the Chinese national team.
林获全能银牌
她在2000年夺得过奥运会银牌
She won a silver medal at 2000 Olympic Games.
中国在那年的体操项目中表现出色
China had a fine showing in gymnastics that year.
你记得那些比赛吗
You remember those games?
悉尼  是吧
Sydney, wasn't it?
她当时多大
How old was she?
十几岁罢了
Barely a teenager.
她随后被开除出了中国队
She was later cut from the Chinese roster
当时她正在捷克共和国
while practicing in the Czech Republic
备战世锦赛
for the World Championships.
原因不明
No reasons given for her termination.
那是什么使凯莉
So what happened that turned Kelly
从一流运动员变成了一流罪犯呢
from a world-class athlete to a world-class criminal?
或许我们该趁凯莉不在
Perhaps we should do a little recon
对她的公寓进行下侦查  里瑟先生
in Kelly's apartment when she steps away, Mr. Reese.
我在凯莉的公寓了  芬奇
I'm inside Kelly's apartment, Finch.
那姑娘不在
No sign of our girl.
看上去  真有点像我的房间
Looks...kind of like my place, actually.
凯莉的联络员提到了"最后一票"  肖女士
Kelly's handler spoke of a "Last job," Ms. Shaw.
既然凯莉有可能伤害他人
If Kelly's likely to hurt someone,
我们就必须提前查明
we need to find out when and where
这一票的时间和地点
the job takes place before it's too late.
要是我想藏起一份绝妙的抢劫计划
If I were gonna hide plans for my ultra-slick heist.
凯莉这里有城市街道地图
Kelly's got street maps of the city here,
标出了一个十字路口
with an intersection marked.
我把照片发给你
I'm sending you some artwork.
是条小巷子
It's a narrow side street,
附近有几个地铁站
several subway stops in the vicinity.
在我看来  是极好的交通要塞
It sounds to me like a good choke point
有多条逃跑线路
with multiple escape routes.
我想我们找到凯莉下一票的地点了
I think we found the location of Kelly's next job.
不只是这些
That's not all we found.
这里还有份研究资料
I've got research here,
关于什么圣经的  古腾堡圣经
something about a Bible, the Gutenberg Bible?
古腾堡圣经
The Gutenberg Bible?
纽约新闻报
最后机会
稀世古腾堡圣经即将离开纽约
正在世界巡展
It's on a world tour.
明天将离开纽约  前往意大利威尼斯
It's leaving New York tomorrow for Venice, Italy.
现在正在转移交接
It's in transit right now.
路障
Spike strip.
芬奇  我看凯莉是准备下狠手了
Finch, I think Kelly's about to do something really violent.
你不知道自己在干什么
You don't know what you're doing.
我看我又一次正确的地点  正确的时间了
I guess I was in the right place at the right time again.
我得拦住他们
I needed to stop them.
现在晚了
Now it's too late.
接吧
Answer it.
西里尔
Cyril.
进展如何
How did it go?
我没拿到
I didn't get it.
不好意思  我刚才还以为你说你没拿到
Excuse me. For a moment, I thought you said you didn't get it.
我没有拿到圣经  西里尔
I didn't get the Bible, Cyril.
但我还有机会
But I still can.
我会想出办法
I'll think of something.
你知不知道后果多严重
Do you have any idea what's at stake,
知不知道这值多少钱
how much money we're talking about?
我在布拉格的伙伴们可不会善待
My associates in Prague don't take kindly
欠了他们债的人
to people who welch on their debt.
温馨提示一下
Let me remind you.
宝贝
你好吗
妈咪  是你吗
Mommy, is that you?
是我  凯
It's me, Kai.
是我  宝贝
It's me, baby.
不要怕
我刚刚听到的是"妈咪"吗
Did I just hear the word "Mommy"?
我们铸成大错了
We've made a terrible mistake.
真不明白你干嘛非为难自己
I don't know why you had to make it so hard on yourself.
这位挺不安分  芬奇
Got a feisty one here, Finch.
你们俩乖乖玩会儿
You two play nice.
我就  拿枪坐这儿了
I'm just gonna sit over here with my gun.
林女士  你可能不相信我
Ms. Lin, you're not going to believe me,
但我帮助别人
but I'm someone who helps people.
就像你帮助我女儿吗
Like you helped my daughter.
我知道你很多事  你的奥运生涯
I know a lot about you, your Olympic career.
你一无所知
You don't know anything.
如果你允许的话  我想了解
I'd like to know more, if you'd permit.
犯罪似乎并非你的本意
You don't seem to commit crimes of your own volition.
但你也并不介意犯下这些罪行
But you also don't seem to mind doing it, either.
我想你很久没有  或者说从来没有
I'm guessing it's been a while, if ever,
体验过绝望  饥饿
since you were desperate or hungry.
我那时尽量掩饰怀孕的迹象
I hid the pregnancy as long as I could.
肚子开始变大后  我知道一切都结束了
When I started to show, I knew it was all over.
去了欧洲  没钱  没技术
Made my way to Europe-- no money, no skills.
体操没法养活我的宝贝
Gymnastics wouldn't feed my baby.
为了支付生育费用  我当掉了银牌
I pawned my silver medal for the medical care to give birth.
然后溜回那家典当行
Then I broke back into the same pawn shop
偷了一块表
and stole a watch.
我偷盗是为了养活我刚出生的孩子
I stole to feed my newborn.
没想到那家典当行是犯罪团伙的幌子
I didn't know it was a front for criminals.
然后他们追踪到了你
And they tracked you down?
他们要我还债
They wanted me to pay my debt,
我猜他们当时正好缺人帮他们偷东西
and I guess they had an opening on their team for a thief.
你可以拒绝
You could've said no.
他们抢走了凯
They took Kai from me.
我别无选择
I didn't have a choice.
他们保证了会送她回来
They promised to send her
只要完成任务就行
just as soon as the work was done.
那些你杀的人呢
And what about the people you killed?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
有名国际刑警一直在追查你的案子
There's an Interpol agent close on your trail.
他似乎认定你犯下了不少命案
He seems to think that you've left behind quite a body count.
西里尔  肯定是他
Cyril-- it had to have been.
他  他会雇佣那些
He--he hires those people--
流浪汉当诱饵
the decoys, vagrants.
肯定是他在我完成任务离开后下了毒手
He must take care of them after I finish a job and leave town.
他是禽兽
He's a monster.
我不知道有人丧命  我发誓
I didn't know anyone had been hurt, I swear.
那圣经是你需要为他们做的最后一件任务
And the Bible was the last thing you needed to get for them?
太晚了
It's too late.
我本想在运送途中抢下来
I had to grab it in transit.
它已被层层保护
It's protected now.
由对称安保公司负责
Outfit called Symmetric Security Solutions.
西里尔和他的同伙可没什么耐心
Cyril and his partners aren't patient men,
我不知道他们会对凯做什么
and I don't know what they'll do to Kai.
对称安保的公司总部在英国
Symmetric Security is based in the U.K.,
不过在这边有一家分公司
but they have a corporate office here.
就在那里  你确定吗
That's where they took it, you're sure?
确定  就在下城区
I'm sure. It's downtown.
我见过  那大厦坚同堡垒
I've seen it, the building's a fortress.
芬奇  你在干吗
Finch, what are you doing?
小调研
Just a little research,
看看如何进入对称大厦
seeing how accessible Symmetric's building is.
对称安保公司
值得信赖的安保公司
你就没考虑过
Have you considered the option
我们去营救那小姑娘
that we could go rescue the girl?
凯在世界的另一端  肖女士
Kai is halfway around the world, Ms. Shaw.
需要多少时间
How long would that take?
要一阵子  但是
A while, but--
如果她没有这"一阵子"的时间呢
And what if she doesn't have a while?
我想我们只有一个选择了
I think we have only one option here.
把圣经拿到手
We need to get the Bible ourselves.
好吧  我给这窃贼松绑
Fine... I'll cut the thief loose.
我已经给自己松绑了
I already cut myself loose.
好吧  对称安保公司
Okay, Symmetric Security Solutions.
我们得查清大厦设计者是谁  搞清布局
We need to know who designed the building and their offices.
我们要找人帮忙拿到建筑结构图
We'll need someone to help secure architectural designs,
不行就偷
steal them if we have to,
然后再策划行动
then develop our operation--
或者只要打电话给认识安保人员的纽约警察
Or just call someone from the NYPD with friends in security,
那些安保人员能拿到这些东西
who can get you those kinds of things.
没错  哥有关系
Yeah, that's right, I know people.
这地方真不错
This is a nice place.
对称安保公司办公室位于金融区
Symmetric Security's offices occupy the top five floors
一栋70层高的建筑里的最高五层
of a 70-story tower in the financial district.
十八点整
At precisely 1800 hours,
结束营业
business operations cease,
所有楼梯和电梯都封闭
whereupon all stair and elevator traffic is locked out,
只有安保森严的车库留有一台服务电梯运行
leaving a lone service elevator in the secured parking garage
这是上高层的唯一通道
as the only way to get to the upper floors.
从内部
From the inside.
这可不是普通的安保公司
This is not your average security company.
对于窃贼
When it comes to thieves,
他们的座右铭是"不能阻止  就地消灭"
their motto is "Deter or eliminate."
对称公司的楼层
The Symmetric floor is protected
有武装安保人员守着
by armed guards and panoramic hemisphere cameras
还有360度全景摄像头
with 360-degree coverage.
圣经会存放在70层
The Bible will be held on the 70th floor,
六个加密房间之一
in one of six secure rooms
那里专门用来存放高价品
where they keep high-value items.
可惜我们没法知道
Sadly, there's no way to know which room
是在哪间存放
they'll hold our item.
不管是哪间  肯定会有
Whatever the room, it's certain to be guarded
生物识别指纹扫描仪
by a biometric fingerprint scan
用来检测进入者五个手指的指纹
which can detect the prints on all five fingertips
以及体温
and also the user's body heat.
在房间里有红外线运动感应器
Inside the rooms, there are I.R. motion sensors
和两米多高的笼子
and an 8-foot-tall cage,
带报警器  带电  保护着物品
alarmed and electrified, that surrounds the object.
笼子自身也带感应器
The cages themselves have perimeter sensors
能探测六米之内的运动
that can detect movement within 20 feet.
简直是闲庭信步
Just your average walk in the park.
他们是行业翘楚
They're the best in the business.
这家公司的负责人非常出色
Whoever's running this company is on top of their game.
而且"爱惜"名誉
And no doubt love their reputation.
我想我该见见对称公司的人
I think it's time I met with someone at Symmetric.
好
Okay.
我是布沙尔特工
This is Agent Bouchard speaking.
我是纽约警局的莱奈尔・弗斯科警探
This is detective Lionel Fusco with the NYPD
第八分局的
down here at the Eighth Precinct.
我之前在市区追查
I was in the village running down a lead
一起盗窃案
on some stolen property for a larceny case.
我看到有个人符合
I saw someone who matched the description
国际刑警通告的描述
of an Interpol notice you have up.
华人女性  二三十岁
Chinese woman, late 20s, eaerly 30s.
你是不是在追个窃贼啊
You hunting down a thief or something?
是的  警探  有什么能帮你
I am, Detective. What do you need from me?
我有点捉襟见肘了
You know, I'm stretched a little thin.
要是你愿意的话  可以去她公寓看看
But if you wanted, you could go sit on the apartment.
如果发现好料
If you get anything juicy,
麻烦给我透一点儿
you could slip it back to me here.
好的  [法语]谢谢
Yes. Merci.
地址是哪里
What is the address?
3D打印机说明书
接到报警这里有车被偷
I got a report of a stolen car in the area.
根据描述就是这辆
The description matches this one.
不可能
That's impossible.
这车属于我工作的那家安保公司
This car belongs to the security company I work for.
我是主管
I'm the supervisor.
给  查吧
Here, check it out.
纽约州  驾照
法罗・塞缪尔
从我拿到的指纹看来
Based on the prints I'm getting,
我敢说这家伙不怎么爱洗手
I can tell this guy doesn't wash his hands very much.
很有参考价值  警探
That's informative, Detective.
我马上就能搞到全套隐约指纹了
I'll have a nice set of latent prints in a few.
不错嘛  莱奈尔
Not bad, Lionel.
芬奇  你有没有查出西里尔
Finch, you find anything else about Cyril
或是关押小姑娘的捷克人的信息
or the Czechs holding the girl?
大部分是推测
Speculation, mostly.
黑帮会掩盖行踪
This syndicate covers their tracks.
根据盗窃记录和新闻报道
Based on theft records and news articles,
我相信他们在进行一个勒索阴谋
I believe they're part of an extortion scheme
专门针对珍品文物
that targets culturally significant artifacts
强迫凯莉去实施盗窃
and forces Kelly to steal them.
然后卖给出价最高的卖家
Then they sell them to the highest bidder
或卖回给原主
or back to the owner.
还真是包赚不赔
That's a guaranteed market.
沙特皇室肯定会有意买回
The Saudi Royal family is no doubt interested
属于他们祖先的宝石匕首
in a jeweled dagger belonging to an ancestor.
卢浮宫的管理者多半也愿意
And the administration of the Louvre might pay handsomely
私底下付一大笔钱买回
under the table to recover an artwork
从他们手上失窃的文物
stolen from them in the first place.
我们能信任她吗  凯莉
Do we think we can trust her? Kelly?
完成最后一票吗
To pull off this last job?
我明白  里瑟先生
I hear you, Mr. Reese,
但我们别无选择
but we don't have another alternative.
我们没有收到凯的号码
And just because we didn't receive Kai's number
但并不意味着我们不能保护她
doesn't mean we can't protect her too.
我们的计划是拿到书  救下小姑娘
Our plan is to get the book and save the girl.
万一捷克人在最后关头撤了怎么办
What happens if the Czechs pull out on their end of things?
在处理了  里瑟先生
Working on that, Mr. Reese.
抱歉
Pardon.
我终于找到你了
I finally found you.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你是谁
Who are you?
我们都很清楚对方是谁
We both know exactly who each other are.
你真的很厉害  我承认
You were good, I'll give you that.
我在国际刑警组织说要追踪你时  他们嘲笑我
They laughed at me when I told them who I was after, at Interpol.
我在那么多国家抓过那么多窃贼
I've bagged so many thieves in so many countries,
但是你  我还以为得追踪一辈子了
but you, I thought I'd chase you forever.
你没有任何证据
You can't prove anything.
但是  我们在这儿了
And yet, here we are.
相信我
Trust me.
不管你下次在哪里作案
Whatever you cook up next,
我都会紧跟你之后
I'll be right behind you
带着特警队  和一副手铐
with a SWAT team and a set of shackles.
绝对相信
Hook, line, and sinker.
我是法罗主管
This is Supervisor Farrow.
有什么能效劳的  布沙尔探员
What can I do for you, Agent Bouchard?
我相信有人意图在贵处
I have reason to believe an attempt will be made
实施盗窃  偷一本非常古老的书
on an item at your location, a very old book.
一本圣经  你一定要相信我
A Bible. You have to believe me.
纽约新闻报
最后机会
稀世古腾堡圣经即将离开纽约
您的信誉无可置疑
Your credentials have been authenticated,
所以我们才会通话
only reason we're talking.
您觉得我们应该怎么做
What do you think we should do?
对此威胁要非常非常重视
Take the threat very, very seriously.
我们将启用202号默认安保预案
We'll initiate default security measure 202,
该预案会把物品
which automatically moves an object
自动转移至我们加密层的中心房间
to the central room of our secure floor
以策万全
for safer keeping.
大功告成  芬奇
Jackpot, Finch.
告诉所有人
You can tell everyone
我们有了圣经的具体位置
we have an exact location for the Bible now.
该动手了
Then it's time to go to work.
一切就绪  里瑟先生
Everything's in place, Mr. Reese.
现在只差内应了
We just need our man on the inside.
处理中
I'm on it.
这么说吧  我已经做了
Let's just say I've worked
十五年的顶级安保工作
in high-level security for the past 15 years.
你知道什么是KN2氪开关管吗
Do you know what a KN2 krytron switch tube is?
方便起见  权当我不知道吧
For argument's sake, let's say that I don't.
但按美国政府的法律规定
But the United States government requires me to say
运送任何禁运品或者违法品
that transportation of any contraband or illegal substance--
别跟我扯套话  伙计
Drop the fine print, pal.
据我听来  就没有你们
From what I hear, there hasn't been a transport invented
对称安保公司运不了的货
that your company Symmetric security cannot handle.
特别是  钱不成问题时
Especially when money is no object.
氪是一种冷阴极气体管
A krytron is a cold-cathode gas tube,
通常用来触发核武器
commonly used in triggers on nuclear weapons.
既然我们公司不检查运送的具体货物
And if our company never looks inside the transport,
根不知道有任何违法活动
we're never made aware of any illegal activity.
不如我再请你喝一杯吧
Why don't I buy us another drink?
好了  只要再调暖和一点点
Okay, let's make it just a little warmer around there.
准许进入
纽约水电局
对称安保公司
你的箱子在这里安全过[美国军事基地]诺克斯堡  威利先生
Your case will be safer here than Fort Knox, Mr. Wiley.
扎波先生  营业时间已过
Mr. Zappo, it's after hours.
我是财产资源部经理
And I'm a property resource manager
旁边这位是我们最尊贵的客户
with a high-value client standing beside me.
你给我靠边站
So you'll stand aside.
那您登记下
You'll need to sign in.
你手提箱里真有核武器触发器吗
Do you really have nuclear triggers in that briefcase?
没有
No.
进来了  芬奇
I'm in, Finch.
麻烦把警报关掉
Can someone kill those alarms?
重置下警报器
Reset the alarms.
给纽约警局打电话  来接我们这位朋友
And someone call the NYPD to come and collect our friend.
肖女士  那应该是给你的信号
Ms. Shaw, I believe that's your cue.
在警报器重置前  你有45秒
You have 45 seconds until the alarms reset.
车库  门口有个警察
Garage, there's a 5-0 at the gate,
来接犯人
here for the prisoner.
他说自己正好在附近
He said he was in the area.
就这家伙
This the guy?
他归你了
He's all yours.
他们上钩了
They fell for it.
下一步呢
Where to next?
送我去肯尼迪机场  私人包机航站楼
Take me to JFK, private charter terminal.
我真该开始收费了
I should start charging fares.
别忘了先把每根手指都舔一遍
Don't forget to give each finger a good lick
再扫描
before you scan them.
你说什么
Excuse me?
唾液能冒充汗液
Saliva will simulate sweat
还能仿造出人体的体温
and fake out the body heat feature.
准许进入
肖女士  我做了一段三分钟的
Ms. Shaw, I created a three-minute
监控摄像头循环信号
surveillance loop on the camera feed.
剩下的靠你们自己了
The rest is up to you.
你们确定他敲几下电脑
Your guy is sure his computer trick
就搞定了运动感应器吗
killed the motion sensors?
确定
Yeah.
说是要提高外界温度
Something about turning up ambient air temperature
直到与我们体表温度相同
to match our skin temperatures.
希望他正确
Let's hope he's right.
他永远正确
He's always right.
天  这儿可真热
Damn, it's hot in here.
危
电
险
网
布沙尔探员  看来你赶过来了
Agent Bouchard, I see you took me up on the offer.
多谢你容许我查看
Thank you for letting me check in.
能否让我亲眼看一下那本圣经
Would it be possible for me to actually see the Bible?
没必要
No need.
今晚已经有人企图偷那书了
We already had someone make a run at the book tonight.
你们逮捕她了吗
Did you arrest her?
是个男的  身材高大
It was a guy. A big guy.
国际刑警追捕的那窃贼是女人
The thief Interpol is after is a woman,
我很确定
I'm sure of it--
那女人会用男人当诱饵
a woman who uses male decoys.
法国朋友  我们处理好了
Look, frenchie, we handled it.
我保证  一切尽在掌握
I promise. Everything's under control.
我的手在冒汗
My hands are sweating.
别冒了
Make them stop.
法罗  我们抓住那人之后你有没有上过70楼
Farrow, have you been up on the 70th since we nailed that guy?
什么
What?
没有  我之后一直跟你在一起
No, I've been here with you the entire time since.
电脑显示你的指纹
The computer's saying your fingerprints were used
三分钟前打开了那里的一个加密房间
three minutes ago to open a secure room up there.
全部安保人员  赶去70层
All security teams, converge on the 70th floor.
这不是演习  快
This is not a drill! Let's go!
我们晚了
We're too late.
[法语]是是是  我完全理解
Oui, oui, oui, Je comprends absolument.
我联络了纽约警局
I liaised with the NYPD.
他们正竭尽全力追踪她
They're using every able resource to track.
是  先生  [法语]是
Yes, sir, oui.
我今晚就去乘机
I'll be on a plane tonight.
挂掉电话  上车
Hang up the phone and get in the car.
我们不是偷圣经  布沙尔特工
We didn't steal the Bible, Agent Bouchard,
我们只是稍微  借用下
we merely borrowed it... a bit.
任务完成
Services rendered.
我不干了
No more jobs.
听见没  西里尔
Did you hear me, Cyril?
我退出
I'm out.
我欠你和你布拉格朋友的债已经还清了
My debt is paid to you and your Prague friends.
我要我的女儿
I want my daughter.
我受够了这种生活
I'm done with this life.
我受够了你
And I'm done with you.
你这些年给我们赚了数百万
You've brought us millions over the years,
娇  上千万
Jiao, tens of millions.
这种好事干嘛要结束呢
Why end such a good thing?
你几时不用再为我们工作  由我说了算
You see, you stop working for us when I say you do.
如果你敢逃跑
And if you ever try to run on me,
我的钱一定要讨回来
I'll get my money's worth,
要么从你身上  要么从你女儿身上
out of you or out of your daughter.
不许碰她
Don't you touch her.
凯  比起我可以把她送去的地方  她现在简直如在天堂
Kai? She's in a luxury spa compared to where I could send her.
你想看看吗
Do you want to know?
做你该做的
Do what you must,
但我认为你应该听到真相
but I thought you should hear the truth.
我是布沙尔特工
This is Agent Bouchard,
国际刑警特别罪案科主管
Interpol special crimes directorate.
我要跟我纽约警局的联络人说话
I need to speak with my NYPD liaison.
温馨提示一下如何
How about a little reminder?
你不能放过她吗  西里尔
Can you just let her be, Cyril?
你要知道  你是我的财产
You have to realize, you're property
你女儿也是
and your daughter's property.
永远都是  只要
And you will be, as long as--
搞什么鬼
What the hell is going on?
计划略变  西里尔
Slight change of plans, Cyril.
凯  我是你母亲的朋友
Kai, I'm a friend of your mother's.
来接你回家
I'm here to take you home.
你安全了
You're safe now.
视频里的人是谁
Who was that in the video?
一位朋友
A friend.
我早就想杀掉你了
I wanted to kill you a long time ago.
只是他们说你很有用
But they said you were too useful.
现在不了
Not anymore!
纽约警察  趴下
NYPD! Down on the ground!
举起手来
Hands up!
警官  这人交给我
Officer, I got this one.
我以前很讨厌这些颜色
I used to hate those colors.
通常意味着我得逃了
It usually meant I needed to run.
凯莉不能再逃了
Kelly can't run anymore.
你觉得接下来会怎么样
What do you think happens next?
里瑟先生会把凯
Mr. Reese will be bringing Kai
安全带回美国
back safely to the U.S.
我会用一个非常富有的化名担保她
And a very wealthy alias of mine is sponsoring
获得美国国籍
her citizenship to help speed things along.
那凯莉呢
And Kelly?
凯莉多次触犯法律
Kelly broke the law, repeatedly.
为了结束这一局面  我们不得不让布沙尔特工介入
And to end this situation, we had to bring in Agent Bouchard.
不论怎样
So for better or worse,
她的命运都掌握在他手里了
her fate is in his hands now.
你有五分钟时间
You got five minutes.
不幸的是  既然你是合法美国公民
Unfortunately, since you are a legal U.S. citizen,
我不能按自己的心愿
I can't do what I really want
把你引渡回欧洲
and extradite you back to Europe.
我手里有你很多案子
And there is so much I have you on.
四十起艺术品及文物盗窃
40 counts of art and antiquities theft,
二十个国家非法贩运
and illicit trafficking in 20 countries.
我可以让你在半个地球随便哪里
I could put you away for a lifetime
关上一辈子
on half the continents in the world,
不管你当时是不是被迫
regardless of the duress you were under at the time.
我现在是国际刑警组织的英雄了
I'm a hero with Interpol now.
我找回了圣经
I recovered the Bible
还端掉了布拉格的一个捷克勒索团伙
and took down a cell of Czech extortionists in Prague.
我不知道是怎么办到的  反正功劳是我的
Don't know how I did that, but I'll take credit.
我就算想  现在也不能行差走错
I couldn't do anything wrong now if I tried.
我一直深感惋惜
I always thought it was a shame.
我的犯罪生涯吗
My life of crime?
不
No.
你之前的生涯
Your life before that.
我一直认为你该拿金牌
I always thought you deserved the gold.
谢谢你的朋友们帮忙救了凯
Please, thank your friends for helping to get Kai to safety.
你们都安全了
You're both safe
西里尔和他的同伙都进了监狱
now that Cyril and his thugs ended up in jail...
或是急诊室
or the emergency room.
我不知道能否适应现实世界
I wonder if I'll make it in the real world.
我唯一擅长的就是体操
The only thing I was good at was gymnastics
还有偷窃
and stealing.
我以前唯一擅长的是杀人
The only thing I was good at was killing people,
不过  我在努力了
but I'm workin' on it.
不如试着当妈妈吧
How about you just try being a mom?
我的天
Oh, my--
-凯  -妈咪
- Kai! - Mommy!
天啊  我的宝贝
Oh, my God, my baby.
我想死你了
I missed you so much.
你怎么样  还好吗
How are you? Are you okay?
我爱你 我带你回家
你们要回家了
We're gonna go home.
是的
Yes, we are.
诺克斯堡呢
How about Fort Knox?
觉得咱们能拿下诺克斯堡么
Think we could take Fort Knox?
你是想专业做吗  莱奈尔
You thinking about doing this professionally, Lionel?
-说不好啊  -我不确定  警探
- I mean, you never know. - I don't know, Detective.
金子不易出手
Gold is difficult to move efficiently
在靠不住的市场上会被压价
and not worth its weight in untrustworthy markets.
而钻石
Now diamonds--
我是想说  我们是很棒的团队
All I'm saying is, we all make a pretty good team.
少了一名成员
There's one teammate missing.
那王冠呢
How about the crown jewels?